Ashish M

DevOps Engineer

Mobile: +919901531081

Mail: ashish.kalaburagi@gmail.com

Address: Bengaluru

Summary

Skilled DevOps professional with overall 3 years of experience. Worked in the area of automation using various DevOps tools and Cloud Technologies. Extensive experience with orchestration and configuration management like Terraform and Ansible. Aspiring to work in an enthusiastic, creative and competitive environment that would set opportunities for enhancing and applying my skill and also to contribute towards the organizational growth.

Professional Profile		Have been involved in various table top meetings with various clients
		Travelled to Singapore on a business visa to lead talks on Cloud and
		Devops, which involved planning of migration from On-Prem to Cloud.
		Working knowledge on AWS, Azure and Google Cloud Platform
		Automation and hands-on with DevOps tools like Jenkins, Ansible, Docker,
		Kubernetes and Terraform
		Certified in Kubernetes and Ansible from Udemy
		Scripting: Bash and Powershell
	_	

Skillset

Cloud Platforms	AWS, Azure and Google Cloud Platform
Operating	Ubuntu, RHEL, CentOS, Windows
system	
Scripting	PowerShell, Bash/Shell
Web/App server	Apache, Tomcat
Tools	Git, Jenkins, JFrog, Ansible, Terraform, Docker and
	Kubernetes
Database	MySQL

Experience

DevOps Engineer Mindtree Ltd.

Oct 2016 - Present

ΙM	S Consulting (OCT 2016 - Present)
	Understanding automation possibilities in projects and automating the tasks using different scripting languages and DevOps tools
	Providing solutions to customer requirements and worked on various project proposals
	Developed tool for host level and database level inventory for migration from on-prem to cloud. Wrote platform specific scripts and used Ansible to execute these scripts on the environment in which
	discovery has to be performed
	Solid experience in Linux (Ubuntu, RHEL and CentOS) administration
	Wrote ARM template for orchestrating infrastructure and LAMP stack installation and configuration in instance provisioned
	Experience working in VMWARE environment
	CI/CD pipeline using Git, Maven, Jenkins, JFrog Artifactory, Tomcat and SonarQube for Java Project
	Wrote PowerShell script to monitor utilization of CPU, Memory and Disk space and trigger a mail when the utilization exceeds a certain percentage
	Participated in DevOps hackathon organized by Mindtree where we demonstrated a complete implementation of DevOps for a Java based web application
	Experience with orchestration on major public clouds like AWS and Azure using Terraform
	Proficiency in containerization technologies like Docker and Kubernetes
\Box	Kubernetes cluster creation and containerizing multi-tier lava application and deploying. Worked on

achieving Data persistency, Auto-healing and Auto-scaling

Worked on Kubernetes services like GKE and EKS in public clouds

World's Leading Car-Sharing Network (Dec 2017 – Mar 2018)
Implemented Environment-as-code using Ansible Tower for Disaster Recovery Setup. Development of Ansible playbooks and roles Installed and configured Ansible tower Worked on Dynamic inventory Providing feasible solutions for various issues related to Ansible and AWS
American Multinational Consumer Goods Corporation (Apr 2018 – Aug 2018)
Worked as part of Migration Team in migrating sites from CenturyLink cloud to Azure Wrote ARM template for provisioning VM's for different environments Provisioning of VM using the ARM template Automated the process of decryption of SSL certificates through Bash script
World's Leading Car-Sharing Network (Sept 2018 – Nov 2018)
Migration of servers from On-premise to AWS Wrote terraform templates for provisioning of VM. Automated the stop and start process of EC2 instances in AWS with Lambda functions and triggering it from Cloud Watch Wrote python script for generating AWS monthly report on resources like EC2, RDS, EBS and EIPs for all regions. Used services like Lambda for running the script, Cloud Watch to schedule the trigger, SES for sending Email and S3 for storing reports
World's Leader In Enterprise Cloud Data Management (Dec 2018 – April 2019)
Handle multiple region infrastructure Orchestration and deployment of environment using terraform and chef solo on AWS Bash scripting for various task, which includes copying AMI, RDS snapshot from one region to another, creation of folder structure on linux. Collaborate with team to fix the issues in terraform templates
Multinational Events And Publishing Company (May 2019 - Present)
Worked as Migration Lead for Mailbox and AD migration from On-Prem to O365 Migration Co-ordinated with Architects and Technical Leads for automating migration activities Involved in Discovery and Implementation activities Worked on ADMT tool to migrate AD objects. Used Native Mode and T2T Command line to migrate the mailbox Used MigratonWiz (BitTitan) tool to merge and migrate mailbox
Awards and Recognition + Outstanding Performer for the year 2017-2018
 RCM Top Talent Award 2017-18 Unstoppable award for automating the process in project A-Team awards for displaying team skills during the course of project

+ Master Mind Award for working relentlessly and automating the migration

steps and making the process better and faster

execution

□ Provided and implemented solutions for migration of storage accounts across subscription

MOOC

2016-present

- + Exploring and learning programming skills, DevOps tools and Cloudcomputing
- + Self-learning from Udemy, Edx, SkillShare, Coursera and YouTube

Education

AIET Gulbarga 2012 - 2016 Bachelor of Engineering
(Electronics and Communication)

Declaration:

I hereby affirm that all the above details furnished are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date: 10/15/2019 Thank you Place: Bengaluru Ashish M